有人吗？
Hello?
嘿 嘿 救救我
Hey! Hey! Help me!
去带他出来
Go get him.
你的第一天 菜鸟
Day one, Greenie.
该起床了
Rise and shine.
我觉得他应该干杂活手
He looks like a slopper to me.
我在厨房需要帮忙
I could use some help in the kitchen.
嘿 有人要落跑了
Hey, we got a runner!
好好看清楚吧
Take it all in.
《移动迷宫》
交给你了
He's all yours.
嘿 菜鸟 你好
Hey there, Green Bean.
不要再落跑了 好吗？
You're not gonna run again. Okay?
很好
Good.
我叫艾尔比
My name is Alby.
你能聊聊自己吗？你是谁？
Can you tell me anything about yourself? Who you are?
打哪来的？什么都行
Where you came from? Anything at all.
不行
No.
你能告诉我你的名字吗？
Can you tell me your name?
我什么都想不起来
I, uh, I can't remember anything.
- 我为何什么都不记得？- 没关系
- Why can't I remember anything? - It's okay.
嘿 放松
Hey, relax.
放松
Relax.
这很正常
It's normal.
我们全都经历过
It happens to us all.
你一两天后会想起你的名字的
You'll get your name back in a day or two.
他们只让我们记得这件事
It's the one thing they let us keep.
这是什么地方？
What is this place?
我带你去看看吧
Let me show you.
我们在这里吃饭
We eat here.
在这里睡觉
We sleep here.
我们自己种食物跟搭棚子
We grow our own food. We build our own shelter.
不管我们需要什么 箱子都会提供
Whatever we need, the Box provides.
其余就靠我们自己了
The rest is up to us.
箱子？
The Box?
对 它一个月会上来一次
Yeah. It's sent up once a month
送物资跟一个新菜鸟来
with fresh supplies and a new Greenie.
这个月是你
This month that's you.
恭喜了
Congratulations.
送上来？谁把我们带到这里的？
Sent up? By who, though? Who put us here?
没有人知道
That, we don't know.
- 嘿 艾尔比 你没事吧？- 哈 哈
- Hey, are you all right, Alby? - A-ha!
菜鸟 这是纽特
Green Bean, meet Newt.
我不在的时候就由他负责
When I'm not around, he's in charge.
还好你永远都在
Well, it's a good thing you're always around then.
你刚刚跑得可真快
That was some dash you made earlier.
我一度还以为你可以当行者
For a second, I thought you had the chops to be a runner...
直到你脸栽到地上
...till you face-planted.
好精彩
That was great.
等等 行者？
Wait, a "runner"?
纽特 帮我一个忙 去找查克
Newt, do me a favor. Go find Chuck.
- 好 - 谢了
- All right. - Thanks.
抱歉 参观时间很赶
Look, I'm sorry to rush this.
你上来得有点晚 我们又有很多事要做
You came up a little late, and there's a lot to do.
今晚有特别的计划
We got something special planned tonight.
对 你晚点就知道了
Yeah. You'll see.
希望你没有惧高症
I hope you're not afraid of heights.
上来吧 快
Let's go. Come on.
全部就这么大了
This is all we got.
我们为此辛苦打拚
We've worked hard for it.
如果你尊重这个地方
If you respect this place...
你我就能相安无事
you and I will get along just fine.
外面是什么？
What's out there?
我们只有三条规矩
We only have three rules.
第一 做好你的分内事
First, do your part.
我们没空理白吃白喝的人
No time for any freeloaders.
第二 不能伤害同伴
Second, never harm another Glader.
大家要互相信任才能成功
None of this works unless we have trust.
最重要的是
Most importantly...
千万别到那些墙后面
never go beyond those walls.
菜鸟 懂吗？
Do you understand me, Greenie?
嘿 艾尔比
Hey, Alby!
嘿 查克 你跑去哪了？
Hey, Chuck. Where you been, man?
大家都一样
It's basically the same story for all of us.
我们在箱子里醒来 艾尔比带我们参观
We wake up in the Box, Alby gives us the tour...
然后我们就在这里了
then here we are.
别担心
Don't worry.
你已经比我表现好了
You're already doing better than I did.
他们把我从大笼子拖出来时
I clunked my pants three times
我吓到尿裤三次
before they got me out of the pit.
不会吧
No, come on.
你要去哪？
Dude, where are you going?
我只是想看看
I just wanna see.
你爱怎么看都行
You can look around all you want
但你最好不要过去
but you better not go out there.
为什么？那里有什么？
Why not? What's through there?
不知道 我只知道他们告诉我的事
I don't know. I just know what I'm told.
我们不能离开
And we're not supposed to leave.
嘿 查克 这是新来的菜鸟吗？
Hey, Chuck. New Greenie, huh?
升级的感觉怎么样？
How does it feel to be promoted?
本 感觉很赞
Feels great, Ben.
我以为没人能离开
I thought no one was allowed to leave.
我是说我们不能离开
I said we're not allowed to leave.
他们是行者 不一样
They're different, they're runners.
他们比别人都了解迷宫
They know more about the maze than anyone.
等等 什么？
Wait, what?
什么？
What?
什么？你刚刚说迷宫？
What? You just said "maze."
我有吗？
I did?
对
Yeah.
你要去哪？你在干嘛？
Where are you going? What are you doing?
我只是想看一下
I'm just gonna take a look.
我跟你说过你不行了
I told you, you can't.
没人能离开 尤其不是现在
No one leaves, especially not now.
不安全
It's not safe.
好 我不会进去
Okay, all right, I'm not gonna go.
菜鸟 我们不能再这样碰面了
We gotta stop meeting like this, Greenie.
- 放开我 - 好了 冷静点
- Get off me! - All right! Calm, calm, calm.
- 别碰我 - 不要激动
- Don't touch me! - Whoa! Take it easy!
放轻松
Just relax.
你们有什么毛病？
What the hell is wrong with you guys?
冷静下来 好吗？
Just calm down, all right?
不 好吧 你们为什么不告诉我外面是什么
No, okay? Why won't you tell me what's out there?
我们只是想保护你 这是为了你好
We're just trying to protect you. It's for your own good.
你们不能把我关在这里
You guys can't just keep me here.
- 我不能让你走 - 为什么不行？
- I can't let you leave. - Why not?
什么东西？
What the hell?
下次 我会让你走的
Next time, I'm gonna let you leave.
欢迎来到营地
Welcome to the Glade.
点火吧
Light him up!
菜鸟 第一天还真精彩
Hell of a first day, Greenie.
来
Here.
来点烈的吧
Put some hair on your chest.
哦 天啊 这是什么？
Oh, my God! What is that?
我不知道
I don't even know.
这是盖里的配方
It's Gally's recipe.
商业机密
It's a trade secret.
对 他还是混蛋一个
Yeah, well, he's still an asshole.
他今天救了你一命
He saved your life today.
相信我 迷宫是危险的地方
Trust me. The maze is a dangerous place.
我们被困在这里了吧？
We're trapped here, aren't we?
目前是
For the moment.
不过…
But...
你看到这些人吗？
you see those guys?
火旁边的人？
There, by the fire?
他们是行者
Those are the runners.
中间那个 是米诺
That guy in the middle there, that's Minho.
他是行者的小队长
He's the Keeper of the Runners.
每天早上这些门开启后
Every morning, when those doors open, they run the maze...
他们会进迷宫
mapping it, memorizing it,
画地图 记下来 试着找路离开
trying to find a way out.
他们找多久了？
How long have they been looking?
三年了
Three years.
他们什么都没发现吗？
And they haven't found anything?
说比做容易多了
It's a lot easier said than done.
仔细听
Listen.
听到了吗？
Hear that?
迷宫一直在变化
It's the maze, changing.
每天晚上都会改变
It changes every night.
怎么可能？
How is that even possible?
去问把我们放在这里的人啊
You can ask the people who put us in here,
如果你能见到那些混蛋的话
if you ever meet the bastards.
听着 事实上
Listen, the truth is...
只有行者知道外面有什么
the runners are the only ones who really know what's out there.
他们是我们当中最壮最快的人
They are the strongest and the fastest of us all.
这也是好事
And it's a good thing, too...
如果他们在门关上前没回来
because if they don't make it back before those doors close...
晚上就会困在那里
then they are stuck out there for the night.
从没有人能够在迷宫内活过一晚
And no one has ever survived a night in the maze.
他们会怎样？
What happens to them?
我们叫它们怪兽
Well, we call them Grievers.
当然 没人看过后还能活着说出来
Of course, no one's ever seen one and lived to tell about it.
但迷宫里有怪兽
But they're out there.
好了 你今晚问够了
Right, that's enough questions for one night.
走吧
Come on.
你可是贵宾
You're supposed to be the guest of honor.
哦 不 不 不 来吧 我带你去参观
Oh, no... No! No, come on. Let me show you around.
来吧
Come on.
那是土木手
And there we got the builders.
他们的手很巧
They're very good with their hands...
但脑袋空空
but not a lot going on upstairs.
那是温斯顿
And then we got Winston...
他是开膛手的小队长
he's the Keeper of the Slicers.
我们有两个医生 科林特跟杰夫
And we got two med-jacks, Clint and Jeff.
- 嘿 怎么样？- 纽特
- Hey, what's up? - Yo, Newt.
他们大部分时间都在替开膛手包扎
They spend most of their time bandaging up the slicers.
如果我想当行者呢？
What if I want to be a runner?
我刚刚说的话 你听进去吗？
Have you listened to a word I've just said?
没人想当行者
No one wants to be a runner.
况且 你得被选上才行
And, besides, you gotta get chosen.
被谁选上？
Chosen by who?
菜鸟 怎么样？
What do you say, Greenie?
想让大家看看你的本事吗？
Wanna see what you're made of?
菜鸟 菜鸟 菜鸟
Greenie! Greenie! Greenie!
好
Okay. All right.
菜鸟 规则很简单
The rules are simple, Greenie.
我想办法把你推出圈外
I try to push you out of the circle...
你想办法撑过5秒就行了
you try to last more than five seconds.
准备好了吗？别对菜鸟下手太重
Ready?
Take it easy on the Greenie.
起来吧
Get up, boy.
菜鸟 来吧 我跟你还没完
Come on, Greenie. We're not done yet.
别再叫我菜鸟了
Stop calling me Greenie.
别再叫你菜鸟？
Stop calling you that?
你想要叫啥？蠢货？
What do you wanna be called? Shank?
你们觉得咧？他看来像蠢货吗？
What do you think, boys? Does he look like a Shank?
好惨
Come on!
你知道吗？我决定叫你蠢货了
You know what? I think I've settled on Shank.
菜鸟 干得好
There you go, Greenie!
以菜鸟来说还不赖吧？
Not bad for a Greenie, huh?
托马斯
Thomas.
嘿 托马斯
Thomas. Hey!
托马斯
Thomas!
我想起我的名字了 我叫托马斯
I remember my name. I'm Thomas!
托马斯
Thomas!
托马斯 欢迎你回家
Welcome home, Thomas.
好样的 托马斯
Good job... Thomas.
那是什么？
What the hell was that?
朋友 那是怪兽
That, my friend, was a Griever.
别担心 你跟我们在一起很安全
Don't worry, you're safe here with us.
什么都过不了那些墙
Nothing gets through those walls.
好了 各位
All right, guys.
睡觉去吧 走
Let's tuck it in for the night. Come on.
今天晚上很棒
It was a good night.
干得好
Good job, man.
你跟我们在一起很安全
You're safe here with us.
效果很好
Wicked is good.
外面是什么？
What's out there?
托马斯…
Thomas, Thomas.
你听得到我说话吗？
Can you hear me?
一切即将改变
Everything is going to change.
托马斯
Thomas.
嘘
Shh.
跟我来
Follow me.
这里很平静 是不是吗？
It's peaceful, isn't it?
我知道这很难让人相信 但以前可不是这样
I know it's hard to believe, but it wasn't always this way.
我们有过黑暗的日子
We had dark days.
我们因为恐惧失去很多男孩
We lost a lot of boys to fear.
还有恐慌
To panic.
我们进步了很多
We've come far since then.
建立秩序
Established order...
缔造和平
made peace.
你跟我说这些干嘛？
Yeah. Why are you telling me this?
你与众不同
Because you're not like the others.
充满好奇心
You're curious.
但你是我们的一员了
But you're one of us now.
你得知道这是什么意义
You need to know what that means.
他们怎么了？
What happened to them?
就像我说的
Like I said...
黑暗的日子 托马斯
dark days, Thomas.
有人试过爬上去吗？
Has anyone tried climbing to the top?
试过了 藤蔓没有到最上面
Tried it. The ivy doesn't go all the way to the top.
况且 上去后要去哪？
And besides, where are you gonna go from there?
那箱子呢？下次升上来时…
And what about the Box? You know, next time it comes up...
没用 我们试过了
No, we tried that.
有人在里面箱子就不会下去
The Box won't go back down with someone in it.
- 那如果… - 我们试过了 好吗？
- Okay, what if we... - No, we tried it, all right?
试了两次
Twice.
好吗？相信我
All right? Trust me.
你想得到的我们都试过了
Anything you think of, we've already tried.
只有穿过迷宫才能出去
The only way out of here is through the maze.
听着 你想帮忙吗？
Now, look, you wanna be helpful?
去多挖点肥料给我们
Go dig us up some more fertilizer.
"托马斯 拿肥料就对了"
"Just get the fertilizer, Thomas."
"你们确定我帮不上别的忙吗？"
"Are you sure, guys? I can't help in any other way?"
"不用 拿肥料就好了"
"No, just get the fertilizer.
"你知道在哪 就在树林中央"
"You know where it is. It's just out in the middle of the woods."
你是本 对吗？
You're Ben, right?
我们见过面吗…
I don't know if we ever...
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
放开我
Get the hell off me!
都是你的错
It's your fault.
我看到你了
I saw you.
这是你害的
You did this.
我看到你了
I saw you!
救命啊
Help!
救命 救命啊
Help! Help!
救命啊
Help!
我要杀了你
I'll kill you!
把他压住
Hold him down.
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
本 冷静点
Calm down, Ben.
发生什么事了？
What the hell happened?
- 他刚刚攻击我 - 你没事吧？
- He just attacked me! - Are you okay?
本 冷静
Calm down, Ben.
不…
No. No.
好了 掀开他的衣服
All right, lift his shirt.
掀开他的衣服
Lift his shirt.
不 不 不要…
No! No! Please. Please.
他被袭击了
He's been stung.
在大白天被袭击？
In the middle of the day?
拜托 救救我
Help me, please.
拜托
Please.
拜托 救救我
Please, just help.
把他关进大笼子
Put him in the pit.
大家来帮忙 带他进大笼子
Everybody, help. Take him to the pit.
- 不 - 医生
- No! - Med-jack!
拜托 别这么做
Please don't do it!
本 冷静
Calm down, Ben.
本 好了
Back down, Ben.
听我说 拜托
Listen to me! Please!
拜托 住手
Please, stop, please!
这是他害的
He did this!
拜托 住手 不 拜托 救救我
Please stop! No! No, please! Help me!
他到底怎么了？
So what happened to him?
这叫感染
It's called "The Changing."
人被袭击就会这样
It's what happens when someone gets stung.
听好
Listen.
本被袭击以后话就说不清楚了
We haven't been able to get a clear word out of Ben since it happened.
他说的话完全没道理
He's not making any sense.
情况只会愈来愈糟
And it's only gonna get worse.
感染扩散了 他很危险
The infection is spreading. He's dangerous.
他跟你说了什么？
What did he say to you?
他说他看到我了…
He said he saw me...
这都是我的错
and that this was all my fault.
这怎么会是我的错？
How could this be my fault?
休息一下吧
Get some rest.
- 艾尔比 - 什么事？
- Alby? - Yeah.
他会怎么样？
What's gonna happen to him?
听我说 拜托 你听我说
Just listen to me. Just, please, listen to me!
米诺 拜托
Please, Minho!
艾尔比
Alby!
拜托 不要
No, please. Please, don't.
拜托 别这么做
Please, don't do it.
竿子
Poles!
往前
Move in!
拜托 不要
No, no, no! Please!
拜托 不要 拜托 不要
No, please! Please, don't!
我会变好 拜托 听我说
I can get better! Please, just listen to me!
拜托 住手 拜托
Please, stop, please!
- 把他推进去 - 住手
- Push him in! - Stop!
我会变好
I'll get better!
他现在属于迷宫了
He belongs to the maze now.
你觉得他熬得过吗？
Do you think he might make it?
本？
Ben?
不会
No.
没人在迷宫熬得过一晚
No one survives a night in the maze.
我们只能把他忘了
We just gotta forget about him.
托马斯
Thomas.
效果很好
Wicked is good.
别让他们太轻松了
Don't make it easy on them.
托马斯
Thomas.
一切即将改变
Everything is going to change.
效果很好
Wicked is good.
这会有点痛
This is gonna hurt a little.
效果很好
Wicked is good.
托马斯 你必须抉择
Thomas, you have to choose.
艾尔比为什么要进迷宫？
But why would Alby go into the maze?
他又不是行者
I mean, he's not a runner.
情况不一样了
Things are different now.
艾尔比在日落前要追溯本的路线
Alby went to retrace Ben's footsteps before sundown.
你要帮忙吗？
Are you gonna help?
所以他要去本被袭击的地方…
So he's gonna go back to where Ben was just stung...
艾尔比清楚自己在做什么
Alby knows what he's doing...
好吗？
all right?
他比我们都要清楚
He knows better than any of us.
这是什么意思？
What does that mean?
事情就像你听到的
Well, it's like you have heard, yeah?
每个月 箱子会送一个新人上来
Every month, the Box sends up a new arrival.
但总有人是第一个 对吗？
But someone had to be first, right?
总有人得在营地 独自待一个月
Someone had to have spent a whole month in the Glade, alone.
那个人就是艾尔比
That was Alby.
那一定很辛苦
I mean, it can't have been easy.
但其他男孩开始一个接一个出现后
But when those other boys started coming up, one after the other...
他看清楚事实了
he saw the truth.
他发现最重要的事
And he learned that the most important thing...
就是我们拥有彼此
is that we all have each other.
因为我们全都一起卷进这件事了
Because we're all in this together.
对
Yeah.
菜鸟 好样的
There you go, Greenie.
他们现在应该要回来了
They should be back by now.
万一他们没回来呢？
What happens if they don't make it?
他们会回来的
They're gonna make it.
万一他们没回来会怎样？
What happens if they don't?
他们会回来的
They're gonna make it.
拜托 我们不能派人去找他们吗？
Come on, guys, can't we send someone after them?
这样违反规定
That's against the rules.
他们要嘛回来 要嘛回不来
Either they make it back or they don't.
我们不能冒险再失去人了
We can't risk losing anyone else.
那里
There!
等等 事情不对劲
Wait, something's wrong.
米诺 快点 你可以的
Come on, Minho, you can do it!
快啊
Come on! Go!
快点 你赶得及的
Come on, you can make it!
米诺 你得丢下他
Minho, you gotta leave him!
他们来不及了
They're not gonna make it.
你得丢下他
You gotta leave him!
托马斯 不
Thomas, no!
干得好
Good job.
你刚刚害死自己了
You just killed yourself.
什么？
What?
他怎么了？
What happened to him?
他看来像怎么了？
What does it look like?
他被袭击了
He got stung.
他的头怎么了？
What happened to his head?
我做了该做的事
I did what I had to do.
好 帮我拉他起来
Okay. Okay, help me get him up.
我们得走了 迷宫已经在变化了
We gotta go. The maze is already changing.
嘿 米诺
Hey, Minho!
我们不能把他丢在这里
We can't just leave him here.
我们得拉他起来
We gotta get him up.
快点
Come on.
让他坐下来
Just sit him down. Sit him down.
这样行不通 我们得走了
This isn't going to work. We gotta go.
我们得走了
We gotta go!
等等 你在说什么？我们得把他藏起来
Wait, what are you talking about? We gotta hide him.
- 藏在哪里？- 我不知道
- Where? - I don't know.
你是说我们哪里都不能带他去吗？
Are you telling me there's not a single place we could take him?
听我说 笨蛋 听我说
Listen to me, shuck-face, all right.
看看四周 这里没有地方去
Take a look around. There's nowhere to go!
你不懂
You don't get it.
我们等于死了
We're already dead.
二 三
Two, three...
好
Okay.
你在干嘛？你在干嘛？
What are you doing? What are you doing?
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
我们得走了 现在就得走了
We gotta go. We gotta go now!
不 再一点点 然后绑好
No, no, just a little more and we'll tie it off.
米诺 再一下子
Minho, stay with me.
米诺 加油啊
Stay with me, Minho.
再一点点就好 我们快好了
Just a little more, we're almost there.
- 菜鸟 对不起 - 怎么了？
- I'm sorry, Greenie. - What?
米诺
Minho!
好
Okay.
快点
Come on.
哦 见鬼
Oh, shit!
你这个疯子
You're a crazy son of a bitch.
快点 跟我来 快点
Come on, follow me. Come on!
好 迷宫在变化了 快点
Okay, it's changing. Come on, come on!
这一区要关闭了 来吧
This section is closing. Come on.
我们在这里能甩掉怪兽
We can lose it down here!
托马斯
Thomas!
你还在等什么？快离开
What are you waiting for? Get out of there!
来吧
Come on!
快点 托马斯 不要回头
Come on, Thomas! Don't look back!
快跑
Run!
快走 托马斯 快跑啊
Move it, Thomas! Go on!
快动作 走了 快点
Move your ass! Let's go! Come on!
来吧 菜鸟 走了
Come on, Greenie! Let's go!
托马斯
Thomas!
大家过来
Guys, get up!
查克 我告诉过你了
I told you, Chuck.
他们不会回来了
They're not coming back.
走吧
Let's go.
不会吧
No way.
我抓住他了
I got him, I got him, I got him.
注意 小心
Watch out. Easy.
里面发生什么事了？
What happened out there?
你们怎么出来的？
How did you guys make it out?
你看到怪兽 了？
You saw a Griever?
对 我看到一只了
Yeah, I saw one.
他不只是看到
He didn't just see it.
他杀死怪兽 了
He killed it.
情况起了变化
Things are changing.
这一点不能否认
There's no denying that.
首先 本在大白天被袭击
First, Ben gets stung in broad daylight.
接着是艾尔比
And then Alby.
现在 我们的菜鸟接下责任
And now our Greenie, here, has taken it upon himself...
进了迷宫
to go into the maze.
这明显违反我们的规定
Which is a clear violation of our rules here.
对…
Yeah...
可是他救了艾尔比一命
but he saved Alby's life.
是吗？
Did he?
三年来 我们跟怪兽 和平共存
For 3 years, we have coexisted with these things.
现在 你杀了一只怪兽
And now, you've killed one of them.
谁知道这对我们代表什么意义
Who knows what that could mean for us.
你建议我们该怎么做？
What do you suggest we do?
他必须受到处罚
He has to be punished.
- 拜托 - 他杀了一只怪兽
- Come on. - He killed a Griever!
米诺
Minho.
你跟他一起进了迷宫 你怎么想？
You were there with him. What do you think?
我想…
I think...
我们在这里待了这么久
in all the time we've been here...
没有人杀死过怪兽
no one has ever killed a Griever before.
我转身落跑时
When I turned tail and ran...
这个蠢蠢货留下来救艾尔比
this dumb shank stayed behind to help Alby.
我不知道他是勇敢还是蠢
Look, I don't know if he's brave or stupid.
但不管是什么 都是我们需要的
But whatever it is, we need more of it.
我们就让他当行者吧
I say we make him a runner.
行者？什么？
A runner? What?
米诺 先别急
Minho, let's not jump the gun, here.
托马斯
Thomas! Thomas! Thomas!
你们要替菜鸟欢呼 没关系
If you want to throw the newbie a parade, that's fine.
尽管欢呼
Go ahead.
但我很了解迷宫的一点
But if there is one thing I know about the maze...
那就是你不能…
it is that you do not...
好 等等 我认得那个声音
Okay, wait. I know that sound.
- 箱子又上来了 - 怎么可能
- The Box. It's coming back up. - It shouldn't be.
纽特 你看到什么？
Newt, what do you see?
你有看到吗？
Do you see it?
是个女的
It's a girl.
怎么可能
No way.
我觉得她死了
I think she's dead.
她手上拿了什么？
What's in her hand?
"她是最后一个"
"She's the last one... ever."
这是什么鬼意思？
What the hell does that mean?
托马斯…
Thomas...
你们还是觉得我反应过度吗？
Do you still think I'm overreacting?
杰夫 怎么回事？
Jeff, what's going on?
她是怎么了？她为何醒不过来？
What's the matter with her? Why won't she wake up?
嘿 伙计 你问我该问谁？
Hey man, I got my job the same way you did.
你认得她吗？
Do you recognize her?
不认得
No.
真的？因为她似乎认得你
Really? Because she seemed to recognize you.
纸条的事呢？
What about the note?
晚点再来担心纸条的事
We'll worry about the note later.
我认为你应该现在担心
I think you should worry about it now.
我们现在要处理的事已经够多了
We've got enough to deal with at the moment.
纽特 他说的对
He's right, Newt.
如果箱子不再上来了
If the Box isn't coming back up,
你觉得我们能撑多久？
how long do you think we can last?
没人说箱子不会上来了
No one said that.
先别乱下结论
Let's not jump to any conclusions.
我们等她醒来 了解她知道什么后再说
We'll just wait until she wakes up and see what she knows.
一定有人知道答案
Somebody has gotta have some answers around here.
好
Okay.
- 你要去哪？- 回去迷宫
- Where are you going? - Back into the maze.
嘿 托马斯
Hey, Thomas.
你是怎么了？想找死吗？
What is this with you, huh? A death wish?
你才刚出来就想回去？
You just got out and now you want back in?
纽特说没人看过怪兽 后
Newt said that no one has ever seen a Griever
还能活着聊怪兽 吗？
and lived to tell about it, right?
米诺 我们现在有一个了
Minho, now we have one.
你是说你一点都不好奇吗？
You're telling me you're not even a little bit curious?
并没有
Not really, no.
你有什么计划？
So, what's the plan?
你要去靠自己支解怪兽 吗？
You're gonna go out and dissect that thing all by yourself?
必要的话 我会
I will if I have to.
其他的行者离开了吗？
Have the other runners left yet?
其他的行者今天早上都不干了
The other runners quit this morning.
艾尔比被袭击后
After Alby got stung, they're not
他们不急着回迷宫
in any hurry to get back out there.
你为何急着回去？
Why are you?
我觉得我们也该了解我们面对的到底是什么了
I think it's time we find out what we're really up against.
好吧
All right.
但你不能独自回迷宫
But you're not going back out there alone.
半小时后到树林找我
Meet me in the woods in half-an-hour.
这样够吗？
Will this be enough?
好
Okay.
走吧
Let's go.
快点
Come on!
好恶心
That's disgusting.
里面有东西
There's something in there.
你是说除了怪兽 松饼以外吗？
You mean, besides a Griever pancake?
你在干嘛？
Whoa, what are you doing?
你不是说它死了吗？
I thought you said it was dead.
- 是反射动作吗？- 最好是啦
- Was it a reflex? - You hope.
来吧 想办法把它拔出来吧
Okay, come on. Let's try and pull it out.
大家一起出力 来吧
Everyone get a hand on it. Come on.
准备好了吗？数到三来
All right, ready? On three.
一 二 三
One, two, three!
- 弗赖伊 你没事吧？- 没事 谢了 兄弟
- Are you okay, Fry? - Yeah. Thanks, brother.
那是什么鬼东西？
What the hell is that?
有意思
Interesting.
好 不管那是什么
Okay, whatever it is...
我们能回营地 再讨论吗？
can we take this up back at the Glade?
因为我可不想看到这家伙的朋友
Because I don't want to meet this guy's friends.
他说的对
He's right.
时间晚了 走吧
It's getting late. Come on.
我们找到这个
We found this.
它在怪兽 的体内
It was inside a Griever.
- 我们的物资上有一样的字 - 对
- These are the same letters we get in our supplies. - Yeah.
把我们放在这里的人
Whoever put us here obviously made the Grievers.
显然创造了怪兽
This is the first real clue,
这是第一条真线索 三年多来第一次有收获
the first anything, you've found in over 3 years.
米诺 对吗？
Right, Minho?
对
Right.
纽特 我们得回迷宫
Newt, we gotta go back out there.
谁知道这能让我们找到什么
Who knows where this might lead us.
你知道他想干嘛 对吗？
You see what he's trying to do, right?
先是破坏我们的规定
First he breaks our rules...
然后说服我们完全放弃规定
and then he tries to convince us to abandon them totally.
只有规定能让大家凝聚在一起
The rules are the only thing that have ever held us together.
我们现在为何要质疑这一点？
Why now are we questioning that?
如果艾尔比在这里 你知道他会同意我的话
If Alby was here, you know he'd agree with me.
这个蠢货必须受罚
This shank needs to be punished.
说的对
You're right.
托马斯是打破规定
Thomas broke the rules.
把他关进大笼子一晚 不准吃饭
One night in the pit, and no food.
拜托 纽特 关进大笼子一晚？
Come on, Newt! One night in the pit?
你觉得这会阻止他进迷宫吗？
Do you think that's gonna stop him from going into the maze?
不会
No.
我们不能让非行者想去迷宫就去
And we can't just have non-runners running into the maze whenever they feel like it.
我们正式搞定这件事吧
So let's just make this official.
从明天起 你就是行者了
Starting from tomorrow, you're a runner.
- 盖里… - 弗赖伊 别说了
- Gally... - No, Fry.
纽特 谢了
Thanks, Newt.
嘿 我们要去哪？
Hey, where are we going?
你待会就知道了
You'll see.
这是迷宫
It's the maze.
整座迷宫
All of it.
整座迷宫是啥意思？你们不是还在画地图吗？
What do you mean "all of it"? I thought you were still mapping it.
没有东西可以画了
There's nothing left to map.
我亲自把每一寸都跑遍了
I've run every inch of it myself.
每个循环
Every cycle.
每个模式都是
Every pattern.
如果有出路 我们早就找到了
If there was a way out, we would have found it by now.
你为何没跟任何人说这件事？
Why haven't you told anyone this?
这是艾尔比的决定
It was Alby's call.
大家必须相信我们有机会离开
People needed to believe we had a chance of getting out.
但或许现在…
But maybe now...
我们是真的有机会了
we have a real chance.
你看一下这个
Take a look at this.
一年前 我们开始探索这些外围的区
About a year ago, we started exploring these outer sections.
我们发现墙上印了这些号码
We found these numbers printed on the walls.
第一区到第八区
Sections 1 through 8.
它的运作方式是每天晚上
See, the way it works,
迷宫起变化时
is every night, when the maze changes...
会打开一个新的区
it opens up a new section.
所以今天打开的是第六区
So today, Section 6 was open.
明天是第四区 接着是第八区 然后是第三区
Tomorrow, it will be 4, then 8, then 3.
模式永远不变
The pattern always stays the same.
第七区哪里特别了？
What's so special about 7?
我不知道
I don't know.
但昨晚 在你杀死那只怪兽 时
But last night, when you killed that Griever...
第七区开启了
Section 7 was open.
我认为怪兽 一定从那里来
I think it must be where it comes from.
明天 你跟我要过去了解
Tomorrow, you and I are gonna take a closer look.
你们在干嘛？你们不准进来的
What are you guys doing? You're not allowed in here.
- 抱歉 是… - 是那女孩
- Sorry, it's just the, uh... - It's the girl.
她醒了吗？
Is she awake?
可以这么说
You could say that.
查克 怎么回事？
Chuck, what's going on?
女孩有够棒
Girls are awesome.
别烦我
Leave me alone!
小心头
Watch your head!
喂 你再丢石头… 喔
Hey, throw one more of those things... Ow!
- 走开 - 我们没有恶意
- Go away! - We come in peace!
- 发生什么事了？- 快闪
- What happened? - Just duck!
我觉得她不太喜欢我们
I don't think she likes us very much.
- 你们想怎样？- 我们只想谈谈
- What do you want from me? - We just wanna talk.
我警告你们喔
I'm warning you!
大家快找掩护
Take cover, y'all! Take cover!
嘿 我是托马斯
Hey, it's Thomas! It's Thomas!
我要上去 好吗？
I'm gonna come up, okay?
好
Okay.
就我一个
Just me.
我上来了
I'm coming up.
好 就…
Okay, just...
别激动 好吗？
Easy, all right?
我在哪里？
Where am I?
这是什么地方？
What is this place?
我为何什么都记不得了？
Why can't I remember anything?
这都很正常 好吗？我们全都经历过
This is all normal. Okay? We've all been through this.
好吗？
Okay?
你过两天就会想起你的名字
Your name will come back to you in a couple of days.
- 这件事… - 特蕾莎
- It's the one thing that... - Teresa.
你说什么？
What did you say?
我的名字
My name.
我叫特蕾莎
It's Teresa.
特蕾莎 我是托马斯
Teresa, I'm Thomas.
但我猜你已经知道了吧？
But you already knew that, though, I guess, huh?
他们说我在睡梦中一直喊你的名字
They said I kept saying your name in my sleep.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我不知道
I don't know.
我不记得了
I can't remember.
这里的人都想不起任何事情
None of us here can remember anything.
我们都像你一样醒来就在这里了
We all woke up here just like you did.
嘿 我保证…
Hey, I promise...
我要把刀拿走
I'm gonna take this.
好
Okay.
上面情况怎么样？
What's going on up there?
她要下来吗？
Is she coming down?
嘿 听着 等我们一下 好吗？
Hey, listen, you guys just give us a second, okay?
好
All right.
走吧
Come on.
女生都这样吗？
Is this what all girls are like?
这女的疯了
That girl is crazy.
"她是最后一个" 这是什么意思？
"She's the last one." What does that mean?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
但你上来后 箱子就没下去了
Ever since you came up, that Box hasn't gone back down.
我想这让大家有点担心
I just think it's got everyone a little worried.
尤其是盖里
Especially Gally.
他认为这是我的错
He thinks it's my fault.
你确定你不记得任何其他的事？
Are you sure you don't remember anything else?
我记得水…
I remember water...
感觉就像我溺水了
feeling like I was drowning.
那些脸孔直盯着我看
These faces staring at me.
一个女人的声音说着重复的事
And this woman's voice saying the same thing over and over.
效果很好
"Wicked is good."
自从我来这里后 我就做着这些梦
Ever since I've been here, I've had these dreams.
我以为那是梦
Well, I thought they were dreams.
你…
You...
你在我的梦里
You were there.
你在梦里…
You were there...
你告诉我一切即将改变
and you told me that everything was gonna change.
这是什么意思？
What does it mean?
我不知道 我只有梦到片段
I don't know. I just always get pieces.
其他人什么都不记得吗？
And the others don't remember anything?
不记得
No.
我们为什么不一样？
Why are we different?
我上来时口袋里放了这个
These were in my pocket when I came up.
"效果很好"
"Wicked is good."
要是我们被送来这里是有理由的呢？
What if we were sent here for a reason?
艾尔比
Alby.
我们甚至不知道这东西是啥
We don't even know what this stuff is.
我们不知道是谁送来的
We don't know who sent it.
也不知道这为什么跟你一起上来
Or why it came up here with you.
我们只知道 这东西可能害他没命
For all we know, this thing could kill him.
他已经快没命了
He's already dying.
看看他
Look at him.
情况不可能更糟了
How could this possibly make it any worse?
快点 这值得一试
Come on, it's worth a try.
好吧
All right.
动手吧
Do it.
好
Okay.
你不应该在这里的
You shouldn't be here! You shouldn't be here!
不
No!
小心
Watch out!
拿针筒 放手
Get the syringe! Let go!
有效了
Well, that worked.
好 从现在开始
Okay, from now on...
让一个人留下来全天候看着他
someone stays here and watches him around the clock.
菜鸟 天黑了 走吧
Sundown, Greenie. Time to go.
嘿 你对我到底有什么意见？
Hey, what is your problem with me?
当你出现后一切都变了
Everything started going wrong the minute you showed up.
先是本 接着是艾尔比
First Ben, then Alby...
现在是那女孩
and now the girl.
大家都看到她认得你了
Everybody saw she recognized you.
我敢说你知道她是谁
And I'm betting you know who she is.
盖里
Gally...
你知道 我们不能永远待在这里吧？
you know we can't stay here forever, right?
谁在那里？
Who's there?
是我啦
It's just me.
查克 抱歉
Sorry, Chuck.
来
Here.
吃饱了比较有力气
You'll run better on a full stomach.
查克 谢了
Thanks, Chuck.
嘿 那是什么？
Hey, what do you got there?
刻得挺好的
Wow, that came out pretty damn good.
这是干嘛用的？
What's that for?
要送给我爸妈的
It's for my parents.
你记得你的爸妈？
You remember your parents?
不记得
No.
我是说 我知道我一定有爸妈
I mean, I know I must have them.
不管他们在哪 我相信他们很想我
And wherever they are, I'm sure they miss me...
但我没办法想念他们 因为我不记得他们了
but I can't miss them because I don't remember them.
你觉得你明天进迷宫会发现什么？
What do you think you're gonna find out there tomorrow?
我不知道
Uh, I don't know.
不过查克 如果有出路
But if there's a way out, Chuck,
我跟米诺会找到的
me and Minho are gonna find it.
拿去
Here.
查克 你干嘛把木雕给我？
Chuck, why would you give this to me?
反正我也不记得他们
I can't remember them anyway.
但如果你找到出路
But maybe if you find a way out,
就能替我交给他们
you can give it to them for me.
睡吧
I'll let you get some sleep.
嘿 查克
Hey, Chuck.
过来
Come here.
手伸出来
Put out your hand.
我要你自己交给你爸妈
I want you to give that to them yourself.
我们会离开这里的
We're gonna get out of here.
全部的人都会
All of us.
好吗？
Okay?
我保证
I promise.
- 好 - 好
- Yeah. - All right.
- 晚安 - 兄弟 晚安
- Good night. - Good night, buddy.
菜鸟 今天是大日子
Big day, Greenie.
你确定你不要跳过？
Are you sure you don't wanna sit this one out?
- 拜托 让我出去吧 - 好
- Come on, man. Get me out of here. - All right.
走吧
Let's go!
往这里 内圈快到了
This way. Not much further to the inner ring.
走吧
Let's go!
快点 走这里
Come on! This way.
奇怪
That's strange.
怎么了？
What?
第七区应该下礼拜才会开
Seven is not supposed to be open for another week.
这是什么鬼地方？
What the hell is this place?
我们叫它们刀片
We call them blades.
这是本的上衣吧？
It's Ben's, isn't it?
对
Yeah.
一只怪兽 一定把他拖到这里了
A Griever must have pulled him down here.
我觉得它在指引我们方向
I think it's showing us the way.
- 等等… - 干嘛？
- Wait, wait, wait. - What, what?
这里 走
This way. Come on.
米诺 你看过这个地方吗？
Minho, you ever see this place before?
没有
No.
这只是另一条死路
It's just another dead end.
你确定要进去吗？
Are you sure about this?
不确定
Nope.
怪兽
Grievers.
那是什么鬼？
What the hell was that?
我们得离开这里
We gotta get out of here.
把钥匙给我
Give me the key, give me the key!
快跑
Move, move!
我们得走了 托马斯 快跑
We gotta go! Run, Thomas!
我们会被困住
We're gonna get trapped!
快走
Go! Go!
快走…
Go, go, go!
快跑
Move!
米诺
Minho!
快点 快走 快走 快走
Come on! Let's go, let's go!
快点跑
Come on, move!
继续跑 快走 快走
Keep going! Keep going! Let's go!
快走 走 走
Go, go, go!
快点 别回头
Come on! Don't look back!
快啊
Come on!
哦 见鬼
Oh, shit!
往那里 哇 哇 哇
There! Whoa, whoa, whoa!
刚刚发生什么事了？
What the hell's going on out there?
托马斯 你又干了什么好事了？
What the hell you done now, Thomas?
我们发现一条新的通道
We found something, a new passage.
我们认为那可能是出路
We think it could be a way out.
- 真的吗？- 这是真的
- Really? - It's true.
我们开启一扇门 看到我从来没看过的东西
We opened a door, something I'd never seen before.
我认为怪兽 白天一定躲在那里
I think it must be where the Grievers go during the day.
等等
Wait! Whoa, whoa, whoa...
你是说你们找到怪兽 的巢穴了？
You're saying you found the Grievers' home?
而且你们想要我们进去？
And you want us to go in?
它们进迷宫的路可能是我们的出路
Their way in could be our way out, Chuck.
对 另一边也可能有十几只怪兽
Yeah, or there could be a dozen Grievers on the other side.
事实是托马斯不知道自己在干嘛 又来了
The truth is, Thomas doesn't know what he has done, as usual.
盖里 起码我有做事
Yeah, at least I did something, Gally.
你做过什么事了？
I mean, what have you done?
你只会一直躲在墙后
Aside from hide behind these walls all the time?
菜鸟 让我告诉你一件事
Let me tell you something, Greenie.
你才来三天 好吗？我来三年了
You've been here 3 days, all right? I've been here 3 years!
对 你来三年了 现在还在这里
Yeah, you've been here 3 years and you're still here, Gally!
这告诉了你什么？
What does that tell you?
或许你该开始改变做法了
Maybe you should start doing things a little differently.
或许你该主事 如何？
Maybe you should be in charge, what about that?
嘿 是艾尔比
Hey, it's Alby!
他醒了
He's awake.
他有说什么吗？
Has he said anything?
没有
No.
艾尔比
Alby...
艾尔比 你还好吗？
Alby, are you all right?
嘿 艾尔比
Hey, Alby.
艾尔比 我们可能找到离开迷宫的路了
Alby, we might have just found a way out of the maze.
你听到我说话了吗？我们可以离开了
Do you hear me? We could be getting out of here.
我们不能
We can't.
我们走不了
We can't leave.
他们不会让我们走的
They won't let us.
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
我想起来了
I remember.
你想起来什么了？
What do you remember?
你
You.
托马斯 你一向是他们的最爱
You were always their favorite, Thomas.
一向都是
Always.
你为什么要这么做？
Why did you do this?
你为什么要来这里？
Why did you come here?
温斯顿 怎么了？
Winston, what's going on?
迷宫的门没有关闭
It's the doors. They aren't closing.
查克
Chuck,
去议事室把门挡住
go to the Council Hall and start barricading the doors.
- 温斯顿 你跟他一起去 - 了解
- Winston, you go with him. - Got it.
- 去找其他人 - 叫他们去树林 快去躲起来
- Get the others. - Tell them to go to the forest. Go hide, now!
米诺 我要你去拿所有的武器
Minho, I want you to grab every weapon you can find.
- 我跟你在议事室见 - 走
- I'll meet you at Council Hall. - Let's go.
特蕾莎 你跟我去找艾尔比 好吗？
Teresa, you and I are gonna go get Alby, all right?
好了 大家躲起来
All right, everybody hide!
特蕾莎
Teresa!
快点 快跑
Come on! Run! Run!
快蹲下
Stay down!
快跑
Run!
萨特
Zart!
- 救救我 - 快去村落
- Help me! - Go! Get to the village!
快走…
Go, go, go!
快蹲下 蹲下
Stay down, stay down!
盖里 让我进去
Gally! Let me in, let me in!
- 艾尔比 - 你没事吧？
- Alby! - Are you okay?
怎么回事？
What's going on?
- 它们来了 - 怪兽 吗？
- They're here. - Grievers?
托马斯 我们该怎么办？
Thomas, what do we do?
它袭击到我了
It's got me!
大家快跑
Everybody, run, run, run!
杰夫 快点 快走…
Jeff, come on, go, go, go!
大家 快走 走
Everyone, go, go, go!
继续跑 哦 见鬼
Keep moving! Oh, shit!
艾尔比
Alby!
躲到我后面
Get behind me!
来啊
Come on!
这里 走吧
Over here, let's go!
这里 走吧 来吧
Over here! Let's go! Come on!
这里 来啊
Over here, come on!
温斯顿
Winston!
扶艾尔比进去
Get Alby inside.
查克 进去 快走…
Chuck, get in! Go, go, go!
把门锁上
Lock down the doors!
小心
Careful.
大家退后
Stay back, guys.
大家都没事吧？
Is everyone all right?
救命啊
Help!
- 嘿 快抓住他 - 救命啊
- Hey, grab him! - Help!
小心
Watch out!
查克
Chuck!
- 查克 不 - 抓住他
- Chuck, no! - Grab him!
把他拉回来
Pull him back!
- 救命啊 - 查克 别放手
- Help! - Chuck, don't let go!
废话
No shit!
- 快拉 - 别放开他
- Pull! - Don't let him go!
- 查克 你没事吧？- 我没事
- Chuck, are you okay? - Yeah, I'm fine.
艾尔比 谢了
Thanks, Alby.
艾尔比 小心
Alby! Watch out!
抓住他
Grab him!
托马斯 带他们出去
Thomas, get them out.
艾尔比
Alby!
不 托马斯…
No! Thomas...
- 托马斯 - 别过去
- Thomas! - Don't go out there!
不 托马斯 等等
No, Thomas, wait!
托马斯 等等
Thomas, wait!
大家去哪了？
Where is everybody?
是谁在那边？
Who's that over there?
盖里…
Gally...
托马斯 都是你害的 看看四周
This is all you, Thomas! Look around!
盖里 别过来 这不是托马斯的错
Back off, Gally! It's not Thomas' fault!
你听到艾尔比说什么了
You heard what Alby said!
- 他是他们的一员 - 谁的一员？
- He's one of them! - One of who?
他是他们的人 他们派他来搞破坏
He's one of them, and they sent him here
这下他成功了
to destroy everything, and now he has!
看看四周 托马斯 看看四周啊
Look around, Thomas! Look around!
这都是你的错
This is your fault!
盖里 别过来 这不是托马斯的错
Back off, Gally! This is not Thomas' fault!
你在鬼扯什么？冷静下来
What are you talking about? Calm down.
他们派他过来
They sent him here,
他现在把我们打造的一切都毁了
and now he's destroyed everything that we've built!
你在鬼扯什么？
What are you talking about?
或许他说的对
Maybe he's right.
托马斯…
Thomas...
特蕾莎 我得想起过去的事
I need to remember, Teresa.
托马斯…
Thomas...
- 托马斯 - 不要
- Thomas! - No, don't!
托马斯
Thomas!
查克 拿另一支针筒来
Chuck, get the other syringe!
没事
It's okay.
托马斯 我在这里
Thomas, I'm here.
是谁把我们放在这里的？
Who put us here?
这一点我们不知道
That we don't know.
特蕾莎…
Teresa...
我们为什么要这么做？
why are we doing this?
托马斯 很好
Excellent, Thomas.
跟我来
Come with me.
效果很好 托马斯…
Wicked isn't good. Thomas...
效果很好
Wicked is good.
这怎么会是我的错？
How could this be my fault?
这是你害的
You did this!
我看到你了
I saw you!
我没办法一直看着他们没命
I can't keep watching them die.
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
你到底在想什么？
What the hell were you thinking?
发生什么事了？
What happened?
盖里接管这里了
Gally has taken control.
他说给我们一个选择 不加入他…
He said we had a choice. Either join him...
就在日落时跟你一起被驱逐
or get banished at sundown with you.
其他人同意这么做吗？
And the others agreed to that?
盖里说服大家这一切都是你的缘故
Gally has everyone convinced that you're the reason all this has happened.
他到目前为止没说错
Well, he's been right so far.
你到底在说什么？
What are you talking about?
这个地方…
This place...
不是我们以为的那样
it's not what we thought it was.
这不是监牢 这是测试
It's not a prison, it's a test.
这从我们小时候就开始了
It all started when we were kids.
他们会给我们挑战
They would give us these challenges.
他们拿我们做实验
They were experimenting on us.
然后人们开始不见
And then people started disappearing.
每个月 一个接着一个 很规律
Every month, one after the other, like clockwork.
他们把这些人送去迷宫
They were sending them up into the maze.
对 但不是我们全部的人
Yeah, but not all of us.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
各位 我是他们的一员
Guys, I'm one of them.
我跟把你们放在这里的人共事
The people who put you here, I worked with them.
我观察你们好几年了
I watched you guys for years.
你们在这里的全部期间…
The entire time you have been here...
我都在另一边
I was on the other side of it.
你也一样
So were you.
什么？
What?
特蕾莎 这是我们做的
Teresa, we did this to them.
不
No.
这不可能是真的
That can't be true.
这是 我看到了
It is. I saw it.
如果我们是同伙 他们为何要送我们上来？
Why would they send us up if we were with them?
不重要
It doesn't matter.
他说的对
He's right.
不重要
It doesn't matter.
这一切都不重要
Any of it.
因为来迷宫前的我们已经不存在了
Because the people we were before the maze don't even exist anymore.
创造者解决掉了
These Creators took care of that.
我们现在是谁才重要
But what does matter is who we are now, and what we do...
我们现在做的事也是
right now.
你进入迷宫找到出路
You went into the maze and you found a way out.
对 但如果我没去 艾尔比也不会没命
Yeah, but if I hadn't, Alby would still be alive.
或许吧
Maybe.
但我知道如果他还活着
But I know that if he were here,
他会跟你说一样的话
he would be telling you the exact same thing.
解决问题 收拾残局
Pick your ass up and finish what you started.
因为如果我们坐以待毙
Because if we do nothing...
那就表示艾尔比白白牺牲了 我可不容许这种事
then that means Alby died for nothing, and I can't have that.
好
Okay.
好 但我们得先过盖里那一关
Okay, but we gotta get through Gally first.
太可惜了
This is such a waste.
盖里…
Gally...
驱逐他们感觉不对
It doesn't feel right, man.
万一托马斯说的是对的呢？
Yeah, what if Thomas is right?
说不定他能带领我们回家
Maybe he can lead us home.
这里就是家
We are home.
好吗？
Okay?
我不想再划掉墙上任何一个名字了
I don't wanna have to cross any more names off that wall.
你真的认为驱逐我们能解决事情吗？
You really think banishing us is gonna solve anything?
不
No.
但这不是驱逐
But this isn't a banishing.
这是献祭
It's an offering.
什么？等等
What? Wait!
盖里 你在干嘛？
Gally, what are you doing?
你真的以为在托马斯做出那种事后
You really think I'm gonna let Thomas
我会让他回迷宫吗？
back into the maze after what he has done?
看看四周
Look around you!
看看我们的营地
Look at our Glade!
这是唯一的办法
This is the only way.
怪兽 如愿后
And when the Grievers get what they came here for...
一切就会恢复以往
everything goes back to the way it was.
你们有在听吗？
Are you listening to this?
你们光站在那里干嘛？他疯了
Why are you all just standing there? He's crazy!
你给我闭嘴
You shut up. If you stay here,
留下来 怪兽 就会回来
the Grievers are going to come back.
它们会一而再 再而三回来
They're gonna come back, and they're gonna keep coming back...
直到你们全都死光
until you're all dead!
闭嘴 把他绑起来
Shut up! Tie him up!
你们听到我说话吗？把他绑起来
Do you hear me? I said tie him up!
你真是充满惊奇啊
You're full of surprises, aren't you?
你不必跟我们走 但我们要离开了
You don't have to come with us, but we are leaving.
想一起来的人 这是最后的机会
Anyone else who wants to come, now is your last chance.
别听他的 他只是想吓唬你们
Don't listen to him, he's just trying to scare you.
我不是想吓唬你们 你们已经够害怕了
No, I'm not trying to scare you. You're already scared.
我很害怕
I'm scared.
但我宁可去外面冒险
But I'd rather risk my life out there
也不想在这里耗一辈子
than spending the rest of it in here.
我们不属于这个地方
We don't belong here.
这里不是我们的家
This place isn't our home.
我们被人放在这里
We were put here.
我们困在这里
We were trapped here.
起码 我们在外面还有得选择
At least, out there we have a choice.
我们出得去
We can make it out of here.
我知道
I know that.
对不起
I'm sorry.
盖里 事情结束了
Gally, it's over.
跟我们走吧
Just come with us.
祝你们对抗怪兽 顺利
Good luck against the Grievers.
各位 往这边
Everybody, this way!
大家跟上 我们就快到了
Keep it up, guys, we're almost there!
- 那是怪兽 吗？- 对
- Is it a Griever? - Yeah.
见鬼
Shit.
查克 这你拿着 跟在我们后面
You take this, Chuck. Stay behind us.
没事 跟紧我就对了
It's okay. Just stick with me.
我们通过后 它就会启动将门打开
Once we're through, it will activate and the door will open.
我们团结在一起…
We stay close, we stick together...
共度难关 现在就离开…
we get through this. We get out now...
不成功便成仁
or we die trying.
准备好了吗？
Ready?
好 走吧
All right. Let's go!
起来 小心
Get up, look out!
进逼
Push it!
小心
Look out!
钥匙
The key!
查克 小心边缘
Chuck! Watch the edge!
- 查克 我罩你 - 拉我上去
- I got you, Chuck! - Pull me up!
快点
Come on!
托马斯 托马斯
Thomas! Thomas!
查克？
Chuck?
又有怪兽 来了
We got more coming!
大家冷静
Keep it steady, guys!
有用
It works!
特蕾莎 走
Teresa, go!
- 别往后退 继续前进 - 团结在一起
- Don't back down! Keep pushing! - Stay together!
一定有路可以出去 走吧
There's gotta be a way out! Come on!
小心
Watch it!
门打不开
It won't open!
托马斯 有密码
Thomas! There's a code!
八个数字
Eight numbers!
迷宫的八区
Eight sections of the maze.
- 嘿 米诺 顺序是什么？- 什么？
- Hey, Minho! What's the sequence? - What?
迷宫那些区的顺序是什么？
The sections of the maze, what's the sequence?
七 一
Seven! One!
五 二
Five! Two!
- 六 四 - 注意了
- Six! Four! - Heads up!
米诺
Minho!
米诺 哦
Minho! Oh!
放开我
Get off of me!
杰夫
Jeff!
顺序是什么？快点？
What's the sequence? Come on!
六 四 八
Six! Four! Eight!
三 有了吗？
Three! You got it?
撑住
Keep holding!
快好了 快点
Almost there, come on!
门开了
The door opened!
真的假的？
Seriously?
这里发生什么事了？
What happened here?
他们真的在监视我们
So they were watching us.
从第一天开始
This whole time.
你好
Hello.
我是艾娃·佩琪博士
My name is Doctor Ava Paige.
我是灾后世界狙杀平台实验处处长
I'm Director of Operations of the World Catastrophe Killzone Department.
如果你们正在收看
If you're watching this, that means
就表示你们已成功完成迷宫试验
you have successfully completed the Maze Trials.
我希望我能亲自在场恭喜大家
I wish I could be there in person to congratulate you...
但情况似乎不容许
but circumstances seem to have prevented it.
我相信大家现在一定非常困惑
I'm sure by now, you must all be very confused...
愤怒
angry...
害怕
frightened.
我只能向大家担保 你们所经历的一切
I can only assure you, that everything that's happened to you...
我们对你们所做的一切
everything we've done to you...
都是有理由的
it was all done for a reason.
你们不会记得
You won't remember...
但太阳烤焦了我们的世界
but the Sun has scorched our world.
几十亿人被大火烧死
Billions of lives lost to fire...
因饥荒而死
famine...
全球饱受苦难
suffering on a global scale.
结果不堪想像
The fallout was unimaginable.
之后的情况更糟
What came after was worse.
我们称之为闪焰症
We called it the Flare.
这个致命的病毒会侵袭大脑
A deadly virus that attacks the brain.
它剧烈…
It is violent...
不可预期…
unpredictable...
无法治疗
incurable.
我们原本以为如此
Or so we thought.
后来 能抵抗病毒的新生代出现
In time, a new generation emerged that could survive the virus.
突然间 人类又燃起治愈的希望
Suddenly, there was a reason to hope for a cure.
但找到治疗办法并不容易
But finding it would not be easy.
年轻人得受到测试 甚至牺牲生命
The young would have to be tested, even sacrificed...
局限在严苛的环境内
inside harsh environments...
他们的脑部活动才能接受研究
where their brain activity could be studied.
大家都在努力了解
All in an effort to understand...
是什么让他们与众不同…
what makes them different...
是什么让你们与众不同
what makes you different.
你们或许不明白
You may not realize it...
但你们非常重要
but you're very important.
不幸的是 你们的试炼才刚展开
Unfortunately, your trials have only just begun.
你们不久后将发现
As you will no doubt soon discover,
不是人人都同意本处的作法
not everyone agrees with our methods.
进步的过程缓慢 世人很惧怕
Progress is slow, people are scared.
现在对我们或许为时已晚
It may be too late for us...
对我来说太晚
for me...
但对你们来说并不是
but not for you.
外界在等待
The outside world awaits.
别忘了
Remember...
效果很好
Wicked is good.
迷宫试验结束了吗？
Is it over?
她说我们很重要
She said we were important.
我们现在该怎么办？
What are we supposed to do now?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们离开这里吧
Let's get out of here.
不
No.
- 盖里？- 不要过去
- Gally? - Don't.
他被袭击了
He's been stung.
我们无法离开
We can't leave.
我们离开了 盖里 我们出来了
We did. Gally, we're out.
我们自由了
We're free.
自由？
Free?
你认为我们在外面自由吗？
You think we're free out there?
不
No.
我们无法逃离这个地方的
No, there's no escape from this place.
盖里 听我说
Gally, listen to me.
你脑子糊涂了
You're not thinking straight.
真的
You're not.
我们可以帮你
Now, we can help you.
把枪放下吧
Just put down the gun.
我属于迷宫
I belong to the maze.
把枪放下
Just put down the gun.
我们都属于迷宫
We all do.
托马斯…
Thomas...
查克
Chuck.
哦 见鬼 见鬼
Oh, shit. Shit.
看着我…
Look at me, look at me!
哦 见鬼
Oh, shit!
查克 看着我 好吗？
Chuck, look at me, all right?
有我在 兄弟 撑着点
I got you, buddy. Just hang on.
没事
It's okay.
托马斯…
Thomas, Thomas...
不 查克 你要亲自交给你爸妈
No, Chuck. You're gonna give it to them yourself.
记得吗？我跟你说过了
Remember, I told you that.
拿着
Take it.
不
No.
谢谢
Thank you.
不 查克 你会好的…
No, Chuck, you're gonna get...
查克
Chuck.
查克？嘿
Chuck? Hey.
嘿 查克 别这样
Hey, Chuck, come on!
快点 醒醒啊
Come on, wake up!
天啊
Damn it!
我们逃出来了 别这样
We made it. Come on.
对不起
I'm sorry!
可恶
God damn it!
Damn it!
- 托马斯 - 查克
- Thomas. - Chuck!
查克 起来啊 快点
Get up, Chuck! Come on!
查克
Chuck!
你们不能把他丢在那里
You can't just leave him there!
你们没事吧？
You guys all right?
别担心
Don't worry.
你们安全了
You're safe now.
小子 放轻松
Relax, kid.
一切即将改变
Everything is gonna change.
我想我们可以说 迷宫试验大获成功
I think it's safe to say the Maze Trials were a complete success.
我没想到会有这么多人存活 但…
I wasn't expecting so many survivors, but...
人愈多愈好啊
the more the merrier.
托马斯不断让人惊艳
Thomas continues to surprise and impress.
目前 他们似乎上钩了
And for now, they seem to have taken the bait.
现在说可能还太早
It's too soon to say...
但他们可能是一切的关键
but they could be the key to everything.
我们继续吧
So let's move forward.
该展开第二阶段了
It's time now to begin Phase Two.